<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<dt-example table-type="html" order="1">

<css lib="datatables buttons"/>
<js lib="jquery datatables buttons jszip pdfmake vfsfonts buttons-html5 buttons-print">
<![CDATA[

$(document).ready(function() {
	var printCounter = 0;

	// Append a caption to the table before the DataTables initialisation
	$('#example').append('<caption style="caption-side: bottom">A fictional company\'s staff table.</caption>');

	$('#example').DataTable( {
		dom: 'Bfrtip',
		buttons: [
			'copy',
			{
				extend: 'excel',
				messageTop: 'The information in this table is copyright to Sirius Cybernetics Corp.'
			},
			{
				extend: 'pdf',
				messageBottom: null
			},
			{
				extend: 'print',
				messageTop: function () {
					printCounter++;

					if ( printCounter === 1 ) {
						return 'This is the first time you have printed this document.';
					}
					else {
						return 'You have printed this document '+printCounter+' times';
					}
				},
				messageBottom: null
			}
		]
	} );
} );

]]>
</js>

<title lib="Buttons">Export titles and messages</title>

<info><![CDATA[

**NOTE - STILL IN DEVELOPMENT. Only Excel export works as it should thus far**

The export button types have the ability to include information in addition to that shown in the DataTable - specifically they can show the page title, table captions or custom messages. The following options are supported for `-button copy`, `-button excel`, `-button pdf` and `-button print` (for the full reference of how these parameters can be used, please see the `-api buttons.exportInfo()` documentation):

* `title` - Shown at the very top of the exported document
* `messageTop` - Shown between the title and the table in the exported document
* `messageBottom` - Shown below the exported table

Please note that the CSV export button types do not support these options! Including this type of meta information in a CSV file would make it unreadable to a CSV viewer.

This example demonstrates the use of these options in various configurations:

* `-button copy` uses all of the default (title and caption bottom in this case)
* `-button excel` shows a top message in addition to the title and caption
* `-button pdf` shows only the title and not the caption
* `-button print` shows a top message with a function to derive the text to display, but not the caption.

]]></info>

</dt-example>

