<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<dt-button library="Buttons">
	<name>collection</name>
	<summary>A button which triggers a drop down with another set of buttons</summary>
	<since>1.0.0</since>

	<description>
		The collection button type is integral to Buttons as it provides the ability to show one or more "sub-buttons" in a drop down that is displayed when the button is activated. This provides a method of collecting like buttons and displaying them in a space efficient manner for the end user.

		The key aspect of this button type is the `buttons` option, which is an array of the buttons that you want to show in the drop down. The buttons defined here are exactly the same as any other button and can also be accessed via the API and manipulated as such.
	</description>

	<option type="string" name="text" default="Collection">
		The button's display text. The text can be configured using this option (see `b-init buttons.buttons.text`) or the `buttons.print` option of the DataTables `dt-init language` object.
	</option>

	<option type="string" name="className" default="buttons-collection">
		The button's class name. See `b-init buttons.buttons.className` for details.
	</option>

	<option type="function" name="action">
		Show the collection
	</option>

	<option type="boolean" name="background" default="true">
		Show (`true`) a background element, which can be styled using CSS to visually highlight the collection by fading out the rest of the page, or not (`false`).
	</option>

	<option type="string" name="backgroundClassName" default="dt-button-background">
		Class name to add to the background element if it is enabled.
	</option>

	<option type="array" name="buttons" default="[]">
		The buttons to show in the collection. The elements in this array follow the same rules as the `b-init buttons.buttons` array - i.e. it can contain strings, objects and functions that describe buttons. As of Buttons 1.1 this can also include buttons that trigger other collections to be shown (i.e. nested collections).
	</option>

	<option type="array" name="prefixButtons" default="undefined">
		A list of buttons that should be prefixed to an existing collection (see the `buttons` option). This provides the ability for a button that extends a collection to add items to the _start_ of the collection's sub-buttons. Like the `buttons` option the elements in this array follow the same rules as the `b-init buttons.buttons` array.
	</option>

	<option type="array" name="postfixButtons" default="undefined">
		A list of buttons that should be postfixed to an existing collection (see the `buttons` option). This provides the ability for a button that extends a collection to add items to the _end_ of the collection's sub-buttons. Like the `buttons` option the elements in this array follow the same rules as the `b-init buttons.buttons` array.
	</option>

	<option type="string" name="collectionLayout" default="">
		Layout options for the buttons shown in the collection. This is a string which can have:

		* Position:
			* `-string dropdown` - Drop the collection down from the host button
			* `-string fixed` - Display the collection centred over the window
		* Column layout:
			* `-string columns` - Automatic column display (based on screen size), upto maximum of four columns
			* `-string two-column` - Display in two columns
			* `-string three-column` - Display in three columns
			* `-string four-column` - Display in four columns

		The column layout can be use with the default absolute positioning of the drop down, or with the fixed position layout option. To use fixed positioning and multi-column layout, simply space separate the options - e.g. `fixed columns`.
	</option>

	<option type="integer" name="autoClose" default="false" since="1.1.2">
		Automatically close the collection when a button inside the collection is activated.
	</option>

	<option type="integer" name="fade" default="400">
		Animation speed that the collection is faded in and out of the display. This is an integer value that represents the animation duration in milliseconds. For no animation use the value `0`.
	</option>
	
	<option type="boolean" name="dropup" default="false">
		When `true`, the dropdown collection always drops up. When `false`, the collection drops down or up depending on the available overflow.
	</option>
	
	<option type="string" name="collectionTitle" default="" since="1.5.4">
		Deprecated in Favour of popoverTitle - will be removed version 3.0.0

		A text string to show at the top of a collection. This can be useful for multi-level collections to ensure the end user knows what the current menu refers to.
	</option>

	<option type="string" name="popoverTitle" default="" since="2.0.0">
		A text string to show at the top of a collection. This can be useful for multi-level collections to ensure the end user knows what the current menu refers to.
	</option>

	<option type="string" name="align" default="dt-container" since="1.6.0">
		The horizontal alignment of the popover relative to the button. It may be one of:

		* `-string button-left` - Align to the left of the activation button.
		* `-string button-right` - Align to the right of the activation button.
		* `-string container` - Align to the left and right of the DataTables' container (since 2.2.2)
		* `-string dt-container` - Align to the left of the DataTables' container and span its full width - deprecated, use `container` and the `span` option.
	</option>

	<option type="string" name="span" default="container" since="2.2.2">
		Match the width of the dropdown to the datatables container.:

		* `default` - width of the collection dropdown is defined by the CSS.
		* `-string container` - Span its full width of the DataTables' container (good for large content areas).
	</option>

	<example title="DataTables initialisation: Create an export collection"><![CDATA[
new DataTable('#myTable', {
	layout: {
		topStart: {
			buttons: [
				{
					extend: 'collection',
					text: 'Export',
					buttons: ['csv', 'excel', 'pdf']
				}
			]
		}
	}
});
]]></example>
</dt-button>
