<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<dt-button library="Buttons">
	<name>columnOrder</name>
	<summary>A button that will control the ordering on a single column</summary>
	<since>4.0.0</since>

	<description>
		Buttons created by extending this button type will have the ability to control the ordering of a column - i.e. when activated the table will order by the target column.

		The behaviour of the button will depend on the state of the table:

		* If already ordering by the target column, the ordering will be inverted.
		* If not year ordering by the target column, the first ordering in `-init columns.orderSequence` will be used.

		In both cases the order will immediately be applied and the table redrawn.

		Additionally, this button type makes use of _split_ buttons to allow a tidy UI to be displayed to the end user, while still giving them full control. In this case, the sub-buttons will give the end user the ability to specify which direction of ordering should be applied. If `-init columns.orderSequence` is used to restrict the ordering to a specific direction, the split buttons will not be shown.
	</description>

	<option type="string" name="text">
		The button's display text. By default the button title will match the title of the target column. Please note, that for the sub-buttons, if you wish to translate the `ascending` and `descending` phrases, please use `buttons.order.asc` and `buttons.order.desc`, respectively, in the DataTables `-init language` object.
	</option>

	<option type="string" name="className" default="buttons-collection buttons-column-order">
		The button's class name. See `b-init buttons.buttons.className` for details.
	</option>

	<option type="DataTable.ColumnSelector" name="column" default="undefined">
		A selector for the column that will be managed by this button. You can use a column index, or a selector, as defined by the column selector option. Only a single column should be selected.
	</option>

	<example title="Show the `columnOrder` button"><![CDATA[
new DataTable('#myTable', {
	layout: {
		topStart: {
			buttons: [
				{
					extend: 'columnOrder',
					text: 'Order by Position',
					column: 1
				}
			]
		}
	}
});
]]></example>

</dt-button>
